<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Communicating Space]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Communicating Space]]></description>
        <link>http://communicating.space/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 19:23:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://communicating.space/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 19:23:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About Communicating.Space]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>About Communicating.Space</h1>,<p>Communicating.Space website is a blog where we select important information and news about the space industry and promote them.</p>,<p>We are a group of expert and enthusiasts. Everyday we read and analyse tons of information related to space activities, news, business, and in general everything related to space. </p>,<p>Our is blog is a selection of all this messy and time consuming information, so you can read just what is important!</p>,<p>Our primary focus is on the following topics:</p>,<ul><li>Earth Observation (EO) and Geographic Information Systems (GIS)</li><li>Telecommunications</li><li>Space Flight</li><li>Launchers</li><li>Manned and robotic missions </li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/about-communicatingspace/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9de519c3-aac1-43f6-ae29-343e7839a17f</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 18:30:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Errant EchoStar-3 satellite retired into graveyard orbit - SpaceNews.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Errant EchoStar-3 satellite retired into graveyard orbit - SpaceNews.com</h1><p>WASHINGTON - An EchoStar satellite that stopped obeying commands this summer has since been boosted into a graveyard orbit 350 kilometers above the geostationary belt, EchoStar said Sept. 6. EchoStar-3, a 20-year-old television broadcast satellite from Lockheed Martin, stopped responding to commands in late July during a relocation maneuver and began drifting around the geostationary arc, triggering warnings to satellite operators with nearby spacecraft.</p><img src="http://spacenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/EchoStar-III.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://spacenews.com/errant-echostar-3-satellite-retired-into-graveyard-orbit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c8865fe1-6c99-400a-af23-22b0850665fa</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Nation enlists NASA's help with astronaut training app - SpaceNews.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Space Nation enlists NASA&apos;s help with astronaut training app - SpaceNews.com</h1><p>SAN FRANCISCO - Space Nation, the Finnish startup, announced plans Sept. 6 to work with NASA under a Space Act Agreement to refine the contents of the astronaut training smartphone application it plans to release in February. &quot;We can use NASA&apos;s expertise to make the experience better,&quot; Kalle V&auml;h&auml;-Jaakkola, Space Nation captain and co-founder, said by email.</p><img src="http://spacenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/spacenation.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://spacenews.com/space-nation-enlists-nasas-hep-with-astronaut-training-app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a93cb977-2cfb-4e58-bf4f-3dc8e2ab51de</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:47:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>