<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Communicating Space]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Communicating Space]]></description>
        <link>http://communicating.space/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:32:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://communicating.space/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:32:30 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Taxonomy for the Earth Observation Services Market]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Taxonomy for the Earth Observation Services Market</h1>,<p>Enhancing the perception and performance of the EO service industry</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/a-taxonomy-for-the-earth-observation-services-market/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d812dcf4-aebf-4ea9-b3a3-3d369022adb7</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:31:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX launches X-37B ahead of Hurricane Irma]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX launches X-37B ahead of Hurricane Irma</h1>,<p>WASHINGTON — With Hurricane Irma looming off the Florida coast, SpaceX beat unfavorable weather odds Thursday morning to send the U.S. Air Force’s X-37B reusable spaceplane back into orbit for its fifth classified mission.</p>,<p>A Falcon 9 carrying the Boeing-built X-37B hidden inside its protective shroud lifted off a 10:00 a.m. Eastern from NASA Kennedy Space Center’s Launch Complex 39A. </p>,<p>By noon, the Air Force had declared the launch a success.</p>,<p>This was the first X-37B be launched on board a Falcon 9 and following stage separation, the rocket’s first stage successfully landed at SpaceX’s Landing Zone 1 &nbsp;at Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, Florida, the company said.</p>,<p>Officials at neighboring Patrick Air Force Base said Tuesday that the 45th Space Wing had begun their hurricane preparations sooner than usual so that they could still support today’s launch attempt. On Wednesday, forecasters were giving only a 50 percent chance of acceptable weather for today’s launch, with the odds of favorable conditions shrinking to 40 percent for a backup opportunity Friday. </p>,<p>While X-37B’s mission has been tentatively scheduled to last 270 days, the Air Force has said that could change depending on the testing progress, how the vehicle performs in orbit and conditions at the landing facility.</p>,<p>Read More here:</p>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/517ca3b253caa5bad4206deeb7bb120a/noop.png?input=http%3A%2F%2Fspacenews.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2017%2F09%2FFalcon-9-X-37B-2017-09-07.png"><h1>SpaceX launches X-37B ahead of Hurricane Irma - SpaceNews.com</h1><p>WASHINGTON - With Hurricane Irma looming off the Florida coast, SpaceX beat unfavorable weather odds Thursday morning to send the U.S. Air Force&apos;s X-37B reusable spaceplane back into orbit for its fifth classified mission. A Falcon 9 carrying the Boeing-built X-37B hidden inside its protective shroud lifted off a 10:00 a.m.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/spacex-launches-x-37b-ahead-of-hurricane-irma/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">89c406f7-2b58-4f0c-bf94-161c606e3f5d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:16:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Scientists Know About Climate Change and Hurricanes: QuickTake Q&A]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Scientists Know About Climate Change and Hurricanes: QuickTake Q&amp;A</h1>,<p>These days, as soon as winds hit 74 miles per hour or barometric pressure drops below 990 millibars, people want to know: Is climate change behind this hurricane? It’s an even more pressing question when a giant storm like Harvey is followed by an even more gigantic one like Irma, which itself is being followed by Jose and Katia. Climate scientists continue to wrestle with the connection between global warming and individual storms, but they’re more confident than ever that there’s some linkage.</p>,<p>Read More here:</p>,<article><img src="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/izX5cgpq7C_A/v1/1200x818.jpg"><h1>What Scientists Know About Climate Change and Hurricanes: QuickTake Q&amp;A</h1><p>These days, as soon as winds hit 74 miles per hour or barometric pressure drops below 990 millibars, people want to know: Is climate change behind this hurricane? It&apos;s an even more pressing question when a giant storm like Harvey is followed by an even more gigantic one like Irma, which itself is being followed by Jose and Katia.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/what-scientists-know-about-climate-change-and-hurricanes-qu/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">761b8a8d-9c7b-4d39-9145-820cb7ec094c</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla and SpaceX Share More Than Musk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tesla and SpaceX Share More Than Musk</h1>,<p>Engineers at Tesla Inc. found a quality problem earlier this summer with a cast aluminum auto part that was taking hours to diagnose and fix. They were stumped, so they called in the rocket scientists -- literally.</p>,<p>Tesla engineers reached out to their counterparts at Space Exploration Technologies Corp., who recommended the use of ultrasound sensors to isolate the problem. The solution saved Tesla about eight hours of work per car, an eternity on an assembly line aiming to ramp up to mass-market volumes.</p>,<p>Rocket ships and electric cars may seem like very different ends of the transportation spectrum, but for these two manufacturers, there’s one key link: They share a chief executive officer in Elon Musk. There are less obvious connections, too. The growing behind-the-scenes collaboration that occurs within Musk’s expanding, post-modern empire has spanned from finding stronger, lighter and cheaper materials to developing software to even sharing executives when the need for trusted talent arises.</p>,<p>“In this race to disrupt the world with both electric cars and autonomy as well as space, you don’t really work for Tesla or SpaceX. You just work for Elon Musk,” technology analyst Gene Munster of Loup Ventures said. “You have the most wicked-smart people who can feed off of each other all working for Elon, and he can call on them to help crack various problems.”</p>,<p>Read More here:</p>,<article><img src="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i7uZK5YGsgaU/v0/1200x800.jpg"><h1>Tesla and SpaceX Share More Than Musk</h1><p>Engineers at found a quality problem earlier this summer with a cast aluminum auto part that was taking hours to diagnose and fix. They were stumped, so they called in the rocket scientists -- literally. Tesla engineers reached out to their counterparts at , who recommended the use of ultrasound sensors to isolate the problem.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/tesla-and-spacex-share-more-than-musk/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6d244ee1-c76f-4867-97f3-ac17462309c7</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:55:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EMSR224: Forest fire in Zakynthos Island and North-Eastern Attika, Greece]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EMSR224: Forest fire in Zakynthos Island and North-Eastern Attika, Greece</h1>,<p>For the last number of days, major fires are affecting Greece; The General Secretary for Civil Protection has declared a State of Emergency for the island of Zakynthos and the Kalamos area in the North-Eastern Attika.</p>,<p>Read More here:</p>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/781ec2a49b1ec1ce9e7d2207fca3ac43/noop.png?input=http%3A%2F%2Femergency.copernicus.eu%2Fmapping%2Fsites%2Fall%2Fthemes%2Fgmes960%2Fimages%2FCopernicus_tw_photo.png"><h1>COPERNICUS EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT SERVICE | Copernicus EMS - Mapping</h1><p>Copernicus Emergency Management Service - Mapping is a service funded by European Commission aimed at providing actors in the management of natural and man-made disasters, in particular Civil Protection Authorities and Humanitarian Aid actors, with mapping products based on satellite imagery.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/emsr224-forest-fire-in-zakynthos-island-and-north-eastern-a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1c6738eb-43b3-46d4-aed6-6afb560e4bb3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About Communicating.Space]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>About Communicating.Space</h1>,<p>Communicating.Space website is a blog where we select important information and news about the space industry and promote them.</p>,<p>We are a group of expert and enthusiasts. Everyday we read and analyse tons of information related to space activities, news, business, and in general everything related to space. </p>,<p>Our is blog is a selection of all this messy and time consuming information, so you can read just what is important!</p>,<p>Our primary focus is on the following topics:</p>,<ul><li>Earth Observation (EO) and Geographic Information Systems (GIS)</li><li>Telecommunications</li><li>Space Flight</li><li>Launchers</li><li>Manned and robotic missions </li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://communicating.space/about-communicatingspace/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9de519c3-aac1-43f6-ae29-343e7839a17f</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 18:30:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>